### ANDRES DEL RIO

Toronto, ON – M4X 1L8 (+1)647-563-1135 | addelrio11@gmail.com Website | LinkedIn | GitHub

#### WEB DEVELOPER

Computer Programmer with a passion for web development seeking an entry-level developer position. One year of hands-on experience developing websites using a range of technologies and programming languages. Dedicated to cross-platform compatibility and responsive design. Team player with strong problem-solving and critical thinking skills, highly adaptable to new environments and challenges. fluent in English and Spanish.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front End: HTML, HTML5, CSS, Version Management: Git, GitHub.

JavaScript, Bootstrap, ReactJS, AngularJS, OS: Windows, Mac, UNIX, Linux, IBM.

jQuery, TypeScript IDE: VS Code, Eclipse, IntelliJ IDEA.

Programming Languages: C, C++, Java, Databases: MongoDB.

SQL, Phyton

### WEB DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

- Configured web app servers, using widely used open source software (MERN and MEAN stack) to provide a solution to a business problem.
- Designed and built a portfolio website using ReactJS, Node is and Firebase.
- Created a Twitter Clone using React.js

**Back End:** Node.is, Express.is, Firebase.

- Created security systems including identity management, authentication, authorization, and resource sharing, to control access to web apps by authorized users.
- Skills in software development, mobile development, distributed programming techniques and database administration, security and a variety of operating systems including Windows, UNIX, Linux and IBM Business Computing.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **DCS / DEC in Computer Programming**

January 2019 - April 2020

Seneca College, Canada.

Graduated with Honors: Seneca President's Honour List Award - GPA 4.0

**Bachelor's Degree in Financial Engineering** 

January 2012 – December 2017

Autonomous University of Bucaramanga, Colombia. Member of Corporate Finance Research Group. – GPA 4.0

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Customer Service Representative**

June 2021 - Present

Pay2Day, Toronto, ON.

- Provided face to face, phone, and email support for customers regarding their payday loans, lines of credit and payroll inquires.
- Handled customer complaints, provided appropriate solutions, and identified and assessed customers' needs to achieve satisfaction.
- Upsold services customers, when necessary.
- Worked under pressure in a fast-paced environment.

### **Customer Service Representative**

**January 2018 – June 2018** 

Accedo, Colombia.

- Provided support over chat for a campaign of a telecommunications company from US.
- Handled customer complaints, provided appropriate solutions within the time limits, and Identified and assessed customers' needs to achieve satisfaction.
- Upsold products or services to customers, when necessary.
- Escalated customer complaints and/or calls to managers when necessary.

### **Credit Analyst - Internship**

May 2017 - December 2017

Davivienda Bank, Colombia.

- Provided loan approvals and modified existing loans using AS/400 (IBM System i).
- Evaluated credit data and financial statements from clients to determine the degree of risk involved in lending money to them.
- Entered data into database software and checking to ensure the accuracy of the data inputted.
- Prepared daily, weekly, and monthly reports.

#### **VOLUNTEER WORK**

## Volunteer – Help Desk

**December 2015 – May 2017** 

Fundación Transformar, Piedecuesta, Colombia.

Provided basic IT support and troubleshooting to a non-profit organization that focuses on improving people's health and wellbeing, helping individuals lift themselves out of extreme poverty and get access the opportunities they need to succeed in school and life.

- Supported staff by managing hardware, software or network problems.
- Served as English-Spanish translator between staff and international organizations during events.